Welcome to our training on how to set one-day default handling time.
In this video, we'll show you how to improve your customer delivery promise
by changing your default handling time from two days to one day.
Why is handling time so important?
It's a key part of earning customer trust.
Every offer in the Amazon store comes with a customer delivery promise.
This is the range of dates in which a customer can expect an order to arrive.
The customer delivery promise considers handling time,
which is the number of days needed for a seller to prepare and ship orders;
transit time, which is the number of days your selected carrier needs to deliver packages;
and occasionally, additional buffers to protect your delivery promise
in case of carrier delivery issues or weather events.
It's important that customers receive their orders before the final date of the customer delivery
promise.
Products that arrive late make customers doubt if you can deliver on time.
Late products also hurt your account health.
If a customer sees two offers in the Amazon store that are the same price
but have different customer delivery promises,
they're more likely to choose the offer with the shortest delivery time.
Thus, it's in your best interest to have the most accurate handling time possible.
A 2019 study found that merchant fulfilled sellers in the U.
S.
overestimate the number of days they need for handling time for domestic orders
by an average of 53 percent.
That means that their customer delivery promises are longer than they need to be,
which makes for missed opportunities.
When you created your seller account, your default handling time was set to two business days.
It might be helpful, however, to consider whether or not your orders need that long.
If you can prepare orders more quickly, shortening your handling time will make your
offers more appealing to customers.
Consider switching to a one-day default handling time.
Note that one day does not mean same day.
A one-day handling time means that an order will be prepared and shipped
by the end of the next business day.
You can change handling times on a per-ASIN basis,
but it's a good idea to change your default handling time
if you can prepare most of your orders in one day.
To set your default handling time, go to the seller central home page
and open the settings menu by selecting the gear icon in the upper right.
Select shipping settings and then choose general shipping settings on the next screen.
Scroll down until you find handling time.
If you haven't changed anything since creating your account,
this will be set to two days.
Select edit to the right, select the circle in front of one day
under choose your default handling time, then select save.
It may take up to 30 minutes for the new handling time to be reflected in your delivery promise.
Because setting a new default handling time means adjusting
the customer delivery promise for every one of your ASINs,
we only allow you to change your handling time once every 24 hours.
If you feel that you can process most orders within one day,
but are worried about having more orders than you can handle,
or products in your catalog that require special attention,
we can help.
You can use order handling capacity
to set limits on how many orders you need to fulfill in the day.
If you have some products that take longer to package than others,
you can also set an ASIN specific handling time for those ASINs.
You can find more information about setting order handling capacity
and ASIN specific handling time in other videos from this series,
or by searching for those terms on the Amazon seller central home page.
Remember, having an accurate customer delivery promise
is an important part of being a successful seller.
Customers prefer offers with shorter delivery times,
so if you can process orders in a single day,
setting a one-day default handling time can make your offers more appealing.
This concludes our training on how to set one-day default handling time.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.